<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joy Zhuozhuo Liu</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 22:48:57 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 22:48:57 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Offer Rescission to Facebook Layoffs 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Continued to &lt;a href=&quot;https://liuzz10.github.io/facebook-1&quot;&gt;a previous blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-rescinded-offer&quot;&gt;A Rescinded Offer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was signing the offer with Facebook, they assured me that if I didn’t win the work visa lottery, they would relocate me to Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2022, I waited for a month and received a cold response from HR, notifying me that my offer had been rescinded. It felt like falling into an abyss, and words failed me. At the time, the overall tech industry job market was still active, and offer withdrawals were very rare. However, following Facebook’s rebranding as Meta and a stock price drop, the company started a hiring freeze. Still, they hadn’t mentioned anything about offer withdrawal publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduation was just a month away, and the new grad hiring season had already passed. What should I do? I couldn’t sleep that night, trying to think rationally. I was drafting an email to HR and seeking assistance from a friend of a friend who is a lawyer with the wording. I was grateful to her for her help, especially since she didn’t know me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HR didn’t reply to my email. I’ve lost my last hope. I was truly hopeless this time. I prayed to God, asking Him to grant me the offer. That night, I felt an incredible peaces. I recall it was a Thursday because we had a prayer meeting every Thursday. After the prayer meeting, my pastor and his wife comforted me about my situation. I jokingly told them I should work for them. I felt at peace, not just about losing the offer, but also about forgiving what they did on me, although they don’t need my forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-miracle&quot;&gt;A Miracle&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, I posted my story on LinkedIn, explaining my situation and requesting help from my network to find a job. Surprisingly, my post went viral. I received numerous messages of concern, connection requests, and job opportunities from all directions. I hadn’t anticipated such an outpouring of support from the online community. Many people encouraged me that despite losing the offer, my efforts weren’t in vain, and my skills remained intact, enabling me to secure a new job through hard work. I was very touched by their kind words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around this time, a friend working at Facebook saw my post and forwarded it to the company’s leadership. A few days later, I received my offer back, and Facebook reinstated it. I don’t know what exactly happened, but my offer was back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t believe what just happened. From the offer being rescinded to being reinstated, just one week had passed. In that week, I experienced the coldes of cold and the warmest of warms in my life. Interestingly, nothing changed when I was crying in despair, but when I let go and prepared to move on, the offer miraculously returned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eagerly shared the good news on LinkedIn, along with my favorite Bible verse, Isaiah 41:10, as I experienced God’s faithfulness through it: “Fear not, for I am with you; be not dismayed, for I am your God; I will strengthen you, I will help you, I will uphold you with my righteous right hand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If God hadn’t given this offer back, would I still believe that He is entirely righteous in my thing? I probably should, because the subsequent events showed me that in this world, there are no absolutes of good and bad things, unlike spiritual matters where good and evil are clearly defined. Things we consider good may turn bad, and what’s perceived as bad may transform into something good. When God takes something “good” away, we should avoid looking at it from a single and never-changing perspective, otherwise we’ll add unnecessary worries to ourselves. Just like Facebook’s offer, while it sounded appealing, but the company’s subsequent difficulties, which occurred half a year later, revealed its lack of stability compared to positions in mid-sized companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;vancouver-or-toronto&quot;&gt;Vancouver or Toronto&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company presented me with two choices: Vancouver or Toronto. Going to Toronto had the advantage of the company reimbursing my moving expenses. However, Vancouver is warmer. I lifted up this decision to God, praying that I could make the choice based on what was more benefitical to my spiritual growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pastor mentioned that there was the fantastic church in Vancouver, one whose pastor had written many books he had read. However, it’s a English-speaking church, which means that I’ll have to improve my English in order to grow. Without further hesitation, I decided to commit my faith to this church. After praying, I felt at peace, and the next day, I informed HR of my decision. I’m going to drive to Vancouver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting when I heard that the Puritans used to find a church before seeking for a job, but nowadays, many find a job first and then a church. I’m not saying I’m superior, but making such a decision requires a strong faith which I didn’t have a year ago when I was searching for internships and even 6 months ago when I signed the offer, but after going through numerous trials, I developed that faith in Christ step by step and decision by decision. He used all of these difficulties to purify my faith, removing impurities with each trial, building my characters, and shaping me into who I am now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;canada-here-i-come&quot;&gt;Canada, Here I Come&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company finalized my offer and began the process of applying for a Canada work permit for me. It took me almost 4 months to obtain it, including the month I managed to claim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the offer had been rescinded, I never felt secure again. I wanted to race against time to start working as soon as possible. The fingerprinting appointment in the Bay Area only had available spots a month later. To expedite the process, my mother and I woke up at 6 am, drove to the Canadian visa center in Los Angeles, and embarked on the seemingly endless 300-mile journey along Route 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting my fingerprints done, we went to a Sichuan restaurant in Los Angeles and ordered the spicy fish dish, which we typically have every Christmas. I don’t know when I’ll have this dish with her again. I’ve already missed her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 weeks later, I was notified to provide them once more when we are back in the Bay Area. Ugh, it felt like an unnecessary ordeal, but I had to be patient. So, we drove to Los Angeles for the second time. Thanksfully, there’s no third call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last step was waiting for FedEx to deliver my passport. I was so eager to start my job as soon as possible that I had packed my bags early. FedEx courier finally handed me my passport in a late afternoon, my mother and I held hands and prayed, cried, and anticipated the day we’d be reunited. Saying goodbye to her and to my cat, I went on my last “road trip” in the states with my little car, driving up to the border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Farewell, America! I’m grateful that I know God here and I learnt about technology. However, you made me lose my freedom, my dream, and separated me from my family. You made me start everything anew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued…)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 22:28:45 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/facebook-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/facebook-2</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Offer Rescission to Facebook Layoffs 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a whole year since Meta laid off 11,000 people on November 9, 2022. The company has recovered, started hiring again, and life seems to have moved on for everyone. But for me, it feels like I’m still stuck in that difficult day. The decision to let people go was seen as necessary for Meta’s survival, but for those affected, it was a heartbreaking event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;career-change&quot;&gt;Career Change&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2020, it was my 6th year in the United States. After 2 unsuccessful attempts at the work visa lottery, I decided to pursue a master’s degree in computer science, shifting from psychology to engineering. Over these 6 years, I had witnessed the challenges faced by international students and realized that my existing path was unsustainable. To thrive here, I needed to learn technical skills for more opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2020 to 2021, I spent my days preparing for technical interviews and worked on web development projects at night. Coming from a social science background, I had to invest extra time to catch up on the basics. During Christmas 2020, I spent a little over 70 bucks on Udemy courses, learning JavaScript, Spring, and MERN stack. My resume transformed from initially having only Matlab projects to several more respectable projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-questionable-moment&quot;&gt;A Questionable Moment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February 2021, I started looking for internships with just 6 months of coding experience after my career change. Despite my lack of proficiency, I received several online assessment opportunities thanks to the favorable job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During one such assessment, I faced a coding problem I couldn’t solve, so I sought help from a friend and passed it. Afterward, I felt it was a questionable move, and I looked down on myself. But I couldn’t afford not to get this job. It was a huge temptation for me. At that time, I didn’t fully trust God’s sovereignty. I should have believed that if God intended to provide something, He would, and if He wanted to take it away, nothing could stop Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, I began the job hunt for new grad positions because I was graduating in the next year. In our industry, new grad hiring usually happens a year before graduation, and I managed to secure interviews with some big companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God touched me, and I prayed for His help to maintain my integrity. I wanted to get an offer honorably and glorify Him in my work. But, was I capable of doing so? I wasn’t sure, as the temptation to land a job was overwhelming. Only with a job could I have the chance to stay.
Often, we become aware of our weaknesses and sins only when they manifest, serving as a reminder that God encourages us to turn our gaze towards Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-dramatic-interview&quot;&gt;A Dramatic Interview&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October 2021, something dramatic happened during an interview from Facebook. I had passed the first 3 rounds and was down to the final round. The last interviewer presented a seemingly simple problem. If I solved it, I would secure the offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technical interviews in the computer field differ from traditional interviews; they have a question bank, but the questions are often modified to assess problem-solving skills. Astonishingly, the final question happened to be one of the top three on a coding platform I had been practicing with. I could have easily solved it with my eyes closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that moment, I had to make a decision: pretend not to know the answer and secure the offer, or tell the truth. Initially, the interviewer had mentioned, “If you’ve seen the problem before, please let me know.” If I disclosed that I had seen it before, he might change the question, and I couldn’t guarantee I’d solve the new one. But if I kept silent, I wouldn’t keep my promise to myself. The interviewer would never know, but I would, and so would God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I chose to be honest, even though I felt it might cost me the job. The interviewer changed the question, and I thought, “I’m going to die.” The second problem was one I had solved just two days before, and I could remember it vividly. This time, I hesitated for 2 seconds only and told him that I’ve practiced it before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strangely, a sense of relaxation and relief washed over me, as if I had already aced the interview. The third question was finally unfamiliar but difficult, and I surprisingly solved it somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 50-minute interview felt like two hours. I had a strong feeling that this interview wasn’t just a test of my algorithmic skills; it was a test of my faith. In those moments, I could sense the comforting presence of God, walking with me through the challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I looked back, I wonder if I had failed the last question, would I still be as grateful as I am now, or would I regret my “naivety”? Everyone makes their own choices based on their faith at the time and nobody should judge except God. When we go against God’s law (which we often do), God doesn’t retract His selection due to our momentary weaknesses. Instead, He requires us to acknowledge our sinful nature, repent, and bring us closer to Him through these experiences. What a graceful Lord we have!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;work-visa-lottery&quot;&gt;Work Visa Lottery&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I had received offers from both Amazon and Facebook, I was excited but torn. Both companies were willing to help me with the work visa lottery, but the chances of winning were approximately 30%. If I didn’t win, I couldn’t work legally, as I had already used my 3-years OPT after completing my first master’s degree. So, I only had one option—win the work visa lottery to work legally, or else, the offer would be meaningless. Many people are unaware that the most challenging part for international students isn’t finding a job but obtaining work authorization. Not all jobs generously offer sponsorship for work visas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate that both companies were willing to sponsor me. If both companies applied, my odds would double. However, I hesitated because it would mean potentially breaking one offer if both won, which wasn’t ethical, especially considering that I would be utilizing their legal resources as well. Ultimately, I decided to apply through only one company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a simple belief at the time—I wanted to see where the hardest road would take me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;disappointing-lottery-results&quot;&gt;Disappointing Lottery Results&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not every time leads to a miracle. The 2022 work visa lottery was one of the harshest ever. When I saw the official statistics, I was too upset to eat for a day. As someone who applied with only one offer, my chances of winning were just 26.45%. Why were they lower than expected? Because 13% of people had two or more companies applying for them. For instance, there were individuals with 75 companies vying for their visas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To what lengths will people go to get what they want? Those 75 offers weren’t all genuine, and these individuals may have been in dire need of staying. However, they might not have considered how their self-interest could harm innocent people. Many people leave their home countries, invest years in education and job searching, all for the chance of winning a work visa, only to be defeated so easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t hate them. I dislike the system. The individuals who designed this lottery system knew that such injustices would occur, but they didn’t do anything. It punishes honest people in secret. For a long time, the US was admired for its pursuit of fairness and justice, driven by a reverence for God. However, the administration of this system was the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A year later, H1B fraud is receiving unprecedented attention, and as the saying goes, “Justice may be delayed, but it won’t be denied.” What’s denied is the transient, like a speck of dust. Destiny blew this least significant speck, myself, to the edge of the precipice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued…)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 22:44:45 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/facebook-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/facebook-1</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Difficult Decision for The Future</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have some difficult news to share. I’ve decided to reduce 95% of my mobile apps and to switch back to a basic Nokia-ish phone, which means that some incredible things will be let go - Facebook, Google, Amazon, Apple, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will mean saying goodbye to incredible software that I worked hard to register and have loved using. I’m deeply sorry for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past 3 years, I’ve seen periods of dramatic growth in the number of apps with which I interact. However, I’ve been developing a fear of being without a mobile phone, a condition known as “nomophobia”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To laser-focus on the real world, I will be prioritizing health, quality time, family, and friends and making several structural changes. I view layoffs as a last resort. Before making this difficult decision, I considered many options (e.g., using time-management apps, temporarily freezing accounts, keeping my phone 3 feet away from my bed), but these didn’t end up working very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To some apps that are leaving me: Thank you for working so hard to engage me and get me to spend as much time as possible on you. To some apps: Thank you for selling me products that I don’t necessarily need. To some others: You are awesome, and I will see you on the web app version. To a few: stop recommending MBA programs to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fantastic application should always solve people’s problems instead of creating new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, thanks to those of you who are leaving. I would not have realized all of this and reconsidered how to balance technology and life without your hard work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,
Joy L&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 23:07:07 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/layoff-letter</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/layoff-letter</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>远方的诗，诗在远方</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;当年，学校最火爆的课程莫过于射击课、帅松林的“审美的历程”和王步高的“诗词格律与创作”。也不知道我是扶了多少老奶奶过马路，才攒来这样的人品，在大三和好友肖潇双双选上了王步高老师的课（只有 40 个人能选上~）。从此认识了隐藏在理工科院系中的各路诗仙诗圣、爱上了南京口音、也开启了每周创作一首诗词的极限魔咒当中。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;现在看来，当时的人生阅历极其有限，无非是写景、思乡、再大一点就是人生抱负不能再多了。十年过去了，一切都变了——从和王老师一起过中秋，到王老师仙逝；从一个风花雪月的“文科生”，变成了增删改查的程序员；从写平仄押韵，变成了写变量循环；从想要拯救全世界，到忙不迭地解救自己。有了写诗的素材，却消磨了写诗的情怀。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;此刻，只想把那些诗情画意的点滴积攒起来，提醒自己在追名逐利当中不要迷失。毕竟，再好的工程师也没有留在九年义务教育的课本上，留下来的，反倒是李白杜甫苏轼这样的“伤心人”。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

秋吟

诗心莫把秋心负，
谁道西风总断肠？
鸟尽云飞天气爽，
纷纷绿叶化红妆。

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

绝句

万水千山乘风来，
潇潇洒洒绝尘埃。
平生只爱故乡雪，
下遍他乡无情街。

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

秋夜喜雪

老酿黄花酒，新煨小枣羹。
夜深风愈冷，大雪不饶城。

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

意难平

楚天飞不尽，悲鸟咽三江。
水洗乾坤彻，凌风一夜长。
孤星观日月，老树薄新霜。
对酒当歌浅，沽名事君王！

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

校河思乡（其一）

沱江翻浪岷江平，一去十年不复寻。
犹记红梅经霜好，不疑春色羡鸟吟。
寒鸦点点千山远，人海茫茫一客心。
天意怜予离恨苦，鹧鸪故遣作乡音。

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

校河思乡（其二）

幼时偏爱田间事，饭好呼归每日斜。
最羡牛童卧柳荫，也随白发戏鱼虾。
青波不觉乌泥改，故水应生芦苇花。
且把归思托锦鲤，蜀江深处是吾家！

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

临江仙·京城大雪

雪霁初晴微冷，京城一片朝辉。小园风起玉花吹。才知湿了发，却看鹊双飞。
萧索残凉冬景，几番旧梦难追。留余长叹事皆非。两行清泪下，回见几枝梅。

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

青玉案·二校门

潇潇黄叶经风舞。彩云里、清华路。
寂静喧嚣都一处。
风华犹在，应知今古，冷月梧桐树。
人间正道多歧误，且待明朝笑风雨。
一片冰心君记否？
休将青发，营营换取，一把功名土！

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 23:07:07 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/poetry</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/poetry</guid>
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
        <category>中文</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>《美中不足 Remedial Christianity Series》1</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Book: 《美中不足 Remedial Christianity Series》Chapter 1-3
Author: Rev. Paul Viggiano
Translation: 王兆豐、楊永麗&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-book&quot;&gt;About the book&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;meizhongbuzu/meizhongbuzu1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the cover of the book&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;meizhongbuzu/meizhongbuzu2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;what is 美中不足&quot; /&gt;
It is a collection of sermons from pastor Paul Viggiano at Branch of Hope OPC church in southern California. The author addressed a few critical theological topics/questions that are usually misunderstood by Christians. It is a great book for me because it corrects my misconceptions. I would like to share what I learnt with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-ratings&quot;&gt;My ratings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to understand: 3/5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thickness: 3/5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aha moments: 4/5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Potential target readers: If you are a seeker, the first 5 chapters are highly recommended. For new believers and Christians who seek a solid theological foundation, this book is for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes about ratings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Of course, ratings are subjective :)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A book cannot be decomposed into a few numbers. Thus these numbers are for you to get a big picture only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-basis-of-our-knowledge&quot;&gt;“What is the basis of our knowledge?”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the source of our knowledge? For example, what is the basis of our morality? How do we prove that things that we think are right are indeed right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is your moral standard for accepting homosexuality and refusing pedophilia? Why is one acceptable and the other not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the following answer and logic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; It may be because pedophiles are not lawful or legal.
-&amp;gt; If so, then your morality is probably based on the law.
-&amp;gt; Is everything lawful/legal right? How do we know which laws are right and which are not?
-&amp;gt; You need another layer to back it up, right? What is that?
-&amp;gt; Your conscience; then what is conscience? your experience; then what if your experience changes? Your education; then what if it’s wrong?
-&amp;gt; So far, we have learnt that the basis of our knowledge and morality is unclear.
-&amp;gt; Is there an &lt;em&gt;absolute&lt;/em&gt; basis/foundation/source/starting point to build up our morality? Or does truth exist?
-&amp;gt; A simple answer is: God designed it this way.
-&amp;gt; Problem solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-the-bible&quot;&gt;“Why the Bible?”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ok, I understand that God’s will may be the ultimate basis of everything. But why the Bible?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there should be a way to make the truth perceived and understood by human beings – yes, through books/words/knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to agree with me at this moment, but you can’t deny the great possibility of it either. It would be great if you can hold this possibility and don’t overlook it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sola-scriptura&quot;&gt;Sola Scriptura&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, there’s no evidence in the universe 100% &lt;em&gt;proving&lt;/em&gt; that “Bible = Truth,” like the way we prove a geometry theory. However, there is much evidence &lt;em&gt;pointing to&lt;/em&gt; the fact that “Bible = Truth”, directly or indirectly – scientific findings, historical record, fulfillment of prophecy, change in every Christian’s life, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when preaching the gospel, we do not &lt;em&gt;debate&lt;/em&gt; with non-believers using evidence only (e.g., scientific findings, historical record, fulfillment of prophecy, change in every Christian’s life), even though those are easy to digest for non-believers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 2 reasons for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, it’s because evidence is not the basis of Christians’ knowledge. The ultimate source of a Christian’s knowledge should be the Bible – God’s words. If we try to convince non-believers by holding up strong evidence over God’s will, then the foundation of our faith is no longer &lt;em&gt;God&lt;/em&gt; anymore – the &lt;em&gt;evidence&lt;/em&gt; becomes the basis. That’s what we should be mindful of. (The author cited an excellent comment from Williams. However, I’m not sure which Williams he is, and I can’t find the English original citation either. Please let me know if you know.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the debate will be endless and even meaningless because the two parties hold different bases of knowledge. In fact, even the most eloquent and knowledgeable Christian can’t convince a non-Christian that “Bible = truth,” if the basis of unbelievers’ knowledge is science, logic, empirical evidence, data, etc., whereas Christians’ knowledge comes directly from the Bible. Therefore, the prerequisite to communicate is to let one side realize that their basis is unreliable. For every believer, the Bible eventually replaced whatever they had as their basis of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wait-isnt-that-circular-reasoning&quot;&gt;“Wait, isn’t that circular reasoning?”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above logic may sound ridiculous to unbelievers. When I was a seeker, I didn’t buy it. How could one use the Bible to prove the Bible? I would trust more if one provides reliable historical evidence than one cites the Bible. However, this is problematic in 2 ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, what is “reliable historical evidence”? How reliable is “reliable”? Why should one trust the authors of regular historical books rather than the authors of historical books in the Bible? Both are subjective to some degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, if Christians don’t cite the Bible, what would they cite? If Christians prioritize empirical evidence more than the Bible, that means empirical evidence is the basis of their faith. If “circular reasoning” is the reason that Christians don’t cite the Bible, then logic is the new “bible.” Now that Christians claim that the Bible is the highest authority, it’s reasonable for them to cite whatever they want from the Bible to support their claim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point is that God’s words are the ultimate cause of all other stuff, such as empirical evidence. It doesn’t mean that I am against evidence. In fact, God’s words and evidence are always aligned. However, it is important to differentiate between supporting evidence and the ultimate cause. We should be mindful that the Bible is the basis of our faith. Don’t get lost in “evidence” and forget where we come from when preaching to non-believers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PS. In chapter 2 there’s a great summary on all books in the Bible from Genesis to Revelation.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 23:07:07 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/meizhongbuzu</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/meizhongbuzu</guid>
        
        <category>Christianity</category>
        
        <category>Theology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding sum(FP) and sum(FN) in the context of micro-F1 score</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my presentation on a data mining class today, a peer mentioned a thoughtful question about the micro-F1 score (see the screenshot below) - &lt;strong&gt;the sum of FP and the sum of FN looks equal, are they always equal? If yes, why calculate twice?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;slide.png&quot; alt=&quot;figure 1. A slide of my presentation explaining microaveraged F1 score&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is interesting and here’s my thought after some research and thinking. I think it can be generalized to &lt;strong&gt;“for any confusion matrix, the sum of FP is equal to the sum of FN”&lt;/strong&gt;. In other words,&lt;/p&gt;

\[sum(FP1,...,FPn) = sum(FN1,...,FNn) = sum(all) - sum(diagonals)\]

&lt;p&gt;In the screenshot, sum(all) refers to all numbers. sum(diagonals) refers to the sum of numbers in green boxes. sum(FP1,…,FPn) or sum(FN1,…,FNn) refers to the sum of numbers in red boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to prove it mathematically, but how to understand the equality? An intuitive way thinking about it is that, &lt;strong&gt;since they are all False, a FP of something is the FN of another thing.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, for an orange that’s falsely predicted as an apple, it contributes both to the FP of class Apple and to the FN of class Orange. So for every False prediction, it will contribute to the sum of FP and the sum of FN at the same time. Therefore, the sum should always be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, you might also find the following equation is true. That’s why micro-F1 is usually mentioned alone comparing to macro-F1 which usually mentioned together with macro-precision and macro-recall.&lt;/p&gt;

\[micro_F1 = accuracy = micro_precision = micro_recall\]

&lt;p&gt;But why both terms appear in the expression/formula of micro-F1? I’m not sure the actual reason behind. From my perspective, I think although values are the same, their meaning are different. I don’t think we have to calculate it twice but they appear in the expression probably since they have their own meaning and, moreover, can be corresponding to the single F1 score which can be expressed by TP, FP and FN as well. This is my guess. I think at the implementation-level we probably could just calculate it once and reuse that number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some readings that may be helpful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://towardsdatascience.com/multi-class-metrics-made-simple-part-ii-the-f1-score-ebe8b2c2ca1&quot;&gt;Multi-Class Metrics Made Simple, Part II: the F1-score&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://towardsdatascience.com/micro-macro-weighted-averages-of-f1-score-clearly-explained-b603420b292f&quot;&gt;Micro, Macro &amp;amp; Weighted Averages of F1 Score, Clearly Explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:07:07 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/micro-f1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/micro-f1</guid>
        
        <category>statistics</category>
        
        <category>course</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>《圣洁 Holiness》1</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Book: Holiness
Author: J.C. Ryle
Translation: 李漫波 朱保平&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;引言&quot;&gt;引言&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;个人的圣洁和敬虔在这个时代没有得到足够的重视，教会需要彻底的复兴。针对当今信仰的状况，有几个提示：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;在成圣的教义上，把信心当做唯一需要的事情，是否明智？
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;信心和称义的关系：唯独信心使人称义。”惟有不做工的，只信称罪人为义的　神，他的信就算为义。“（罗 4:5）&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;信心和成圣的关系：既需要信心，也需要个人的努力和做工。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;因此，不要轻看”行为“对于圣洁生命的重要性。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;轻视登山宝训以及保罗书信后半部分中许多对日常圣洁生活的实用劝勉，是否明智？
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;登山宝训（太 5）&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;对于圣洁生活，不能泛泛而谈，而是需要落实到生活中的每一个细节。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;强迫信徒达到”完全“圣洁的状态，是否明智？
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;越是追求圣洁的信徒，越会对自己的不完全有深刻的认识；越蒙属灵的光照，就越看到他们数不清的缺点。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;世上不会有”完全“人，因为老我罪性在身体里面。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;不鼓励信徒分享自己有多”完全“的见证，因为这不是真实的，而且会让软弱的人丧胆&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;许多人说罗马书第 7 章描述的不是成熟圣徒的经历，而是未重生之人的经历，是否明智？
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;改教家和清教徒认为罗马书第 7 章描述的是成熟的圣徒。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;”基督在我们里面“这一表述常常被使用，是否明智？
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;不可轻视圣灵的工作：拣选是圣父的特别工作，救赎中保是圣子的特别工作，成圣是圣灵的特别工作。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;”基督在我们里面“的真正意思是，基督借着他的灵在我们里面（约一 3:24）&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;异端曲解了”基督在我们里面“，认为他们不必为自己的行为负责任，因为只有基督活在他们里面，因此肆无忌惮地犯各样的罪。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;许多人在归信与成圣之间划出一条泾渭分明的界限，是否明智？
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;一些教师把会众分为三类：未归信的、归信的、全然成圣的人，这是不合乎圣经的。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;神的道总是将人分成两类（而不是三类），这两类人之间才有巨大的鸿沟，是生与死、光明与黑暗的区别。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;人士在圣洁/恩典/知识/信心/爱/谦卑/属灵当中渐渐长进的，归信到成圣之间的不是鸿沟。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;归信就意味着被分别为圣给神了。有的教会强调“第二次归信”，实际上”第一次归信”并不是真正的归信，“第二次归信”才是，因此这个分类毫无意义。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;不要想太多与罪争战的事情，只要把自己“交托给上帝”，把自己消极地交在基督手中，是否明智？
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“将自己交托”的理解误区：意思不是“把自己消极地放在别人手中”，而是积极地献上我们自己去服侍（罗 12:1）。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;要像基督的精兵一样去争战、打仗、摔跤。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;不要混淆称义和成圣，称义的重点是“信”，并唯独信；成圣的重点是“警醒、祷告、争战”。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;罪&quot;&gt;罪&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;罪的定义：行为、言语、思想一切不合乎神旨意和律法的举动就是罪。
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;不仅是外在行为，也包括内在的想法计划。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;不仅是做错了的事，也包含应该做却没做的事（…因为我饿了，你们不给我吃。渴了，你们不给我喝（太 25:42））。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;不仅是察觉了的罪，也包含没有察觉到的罪。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;罪的来源：因为亚当夏娃犯罪，我们生来就带着罪性，每个人从生下来就有作恶的倾向。婴儿不是“小天使”，乃是“小罪人”。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;罪的程度
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;身上每一处都被罪玷污：理解力、感情、理性、意志、良心。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;人类所在的每个角落都有罪。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;罪的卑劣
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;人无法得知在圣洁神眼中罪有多么可憎。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;罪可憎的程度之深以至于只有神独生爱子的宝血才能偿还。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;罪的迷惑性
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;人常常低估了罪的邪恶与危险。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;罪常常粉饰得悦人眼目，引得人步入他的陷阱中。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;作者要求我们思想，我们有着怎样深切的理由要谦卑。
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;人类所做过最好的事情，都有需要被神饶恕的地方。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;越被光照，就越能看到自己的罪性。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;作者要求我们思想，我们对神荣耀恩典的福音应该有着怎样的感恩之情。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;对罪有了正确认识之后，可以帮助我们：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;可以分辨“暧昧、模糊、玄妙、缥缈”的神学观念&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;可以分辨“空泛、自由主义”的神学思想&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;可以分辨“追求感觉、着重仪式、形式化”的基督教&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;可以分辨“人能完全成圣”的错误之处&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;可以分辨“对个人圣洁的低标准要求”的错误之处&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;成圣&quot;&gt;成圣&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;成圣的本质
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;定义：成圣是一个人从成为真信徒起，借着他的圣灵，在这个人里面所做的内在的属灵之工。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣是与基督相连的结果。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣是重生的果实。如果我们看不到成圣，那这个人就没有重生。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣是圣灵内住的唯一确实的证据。如果我们看不到成圣，那这个人就没有圣灵。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣是蒙神拣选的唯一可靠的记号。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣总是可以被人观察到的。是一种分别出来的气质、性情、品格和生命形态。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣是每个信徒的责任。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣是需要成长的，在成长过程中呈现出不同的程度。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣需要殷勤地使用圣经中指出的方法，即读经、祷告、主日敬拜、领圣餐等。一个忽视了这些的人，是不会有长进的。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣并不会使一个人免于内在的争战。新人与旧人、肉体与圣灵的争战存在于每一个信徒心理。不仅如此，在越属灵的人心中，这样的征战越激烈。与此同时，内心的平安也越多。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣是讨神喜悦的。尽管我们不是凭行为称义，但是成圣的努力是神期待看到的。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;在末日审判时，成圣是显明我们生命品格的证据。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;成圣是进入天国所必须经历的。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;成圣的标志
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;真正的成圣不是
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;有关信仰的高谈阔论。&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;真正的成圣不在于一时的宗教感觉。&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;真正的成圣不在于外在的形式和外表的敬虔。&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;真正的成圣不是放下应尽的社会责任。&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;真正的成圣不是偶尔做一些正确的行动。&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;真正的成圣是
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;一贯努力遵行耶稣基督的旨意。&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;一贯渴望活出保罗在写给教会书信中所教导的准则。&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;在主动去行的美德上一向殷勤，尤其在彼此相爱的事上。&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;在“被动”去行的美德上一向殷勤，比如在忍耐、温柔和恩慈上。&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;称义和成圣的区别&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;相同点：
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;都是来自神白白的恩典。&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;都是神救赎之工的一部分。&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;称义的人==成圣的人。&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;不同点：
| 称义 | 成圣 |
| ———————————— | —————————————- |
| 将基督的义归算在一个人身上 | 使一个人内心有义 |
| 不是我们自己的义 | 是圣灵做成的我们的义，即便这个义并不完全 |
| 唯靠信心 | 个人努力也很重要 |
| 不分程度，不需要长进 | 有程度之分，需要不断长进 |
| 和我们在神眼中的地位有关 | 和我们内心的道德更新有关 |
| 赋予我们进天国的权力，使我们坦然无惧 | 使我们与天国相称 |
| 不易被他人察觉 | 可以看到果实 |&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 12:20:17 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/holiness</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/holiness</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>Holiness</category>
        
        <category>Christianity</category>
        
        <category>中文</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Operations on heaps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;English:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tW9RyOalyic&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;中文：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iDgY8R9Ywwo&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;无法访问 YTB 的朋友，请前往 (B 站)[https://space.bilibili.com/507554252/channel/series]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 23:07:07 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/heap_operations</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/heap_operations</guid>
        
        <category>youtube channel</category>
        
        <category>algorithms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is a heap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;English:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QyvfR4p4h1c&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;中文：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yrp21TXuxjA&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;无法访问 YTB 的朋友，请前往 (B 站)[https://space.bilibili.com/507554252/channel/series]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 08:27:22 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/heap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/heap</guid>
        
        <category>youtube channel</category>
        
        <category>algorithms</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>《悔改真义》3：悔改的试炼、拦阻和良方</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Book: Doctrine of Repentance
Author: Thomas Watson
Translation: 赵中辉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;悔改的试炼与安慰&quot;&gt;悔改的试炼与安慰&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;悔改的试炼&quot;&gt;悔改的试炼&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“你看，你们依着上帝的意思而忧愁，这在你们当中产生了何等的殷勤、甚至辩白、甚至愤慨、甚至恐惧、甚至渴望、甚至热忱、甚至责罚。在这一切事上，你们都表明自己是无可指责的。”（林后 7:11）&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;林后 7:11 罗列了七项悔改的表现：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;殷勤。&lt;/strong&gt;迫切地逃避罪恶。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;辩白。&lt;/strong&gt;指的是悔改的人心中再无罪疚，可以在撒旦面前为自己辩护。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;愤慨。&lt;/strong&gt;悔改的人为罪厌恶自己，神就加倍喜悦我们。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;恐惧。&lt;/strong&gt;悔改的心充满恐惧，害怕因为自己做得不够好而再次陷入试探，是一种谦卑的心态。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;渴望。&lt;/strong&gt;悔改的人渴望更有能力抵挡试探，渴望脱离罪的辖制，渴望永葆圣洁，像使徒保罗那样呼喊：“誰能救我脫離這取死的身體呢？”（罗 7:24）。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;热忱。&lt;/strong&gt;渴望圣洁的心必然会带来热忱的行为，热心于追求天国的荣耀，持守神圣的忧愁、为神的国奋不顾身。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;责罚。&lt;/strong&gt;悔改的人责罚那些曾经绊倒过自己的事物，这一点作者举了好几个例子说明这一悔改的果子。
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cranmer 曾用右手簽訂教皇的條款，就自己對付自己，在受刑時先把右手放進火裏去。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;大衛犯罪玷污他的床，悔改後，以眼淚浸透了床（诗 6:6）。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;以色列拜偶像犯罪，後來把偶像羞辱淨盡，“你雕刻偶像所包的銀子……你要玷污”（赛 30:22）。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;以色列妇人频频妆扮更衣，用镜子炫耀自己的美貌，后来为了对付这事，也因为热心，就把镜子献上用在上帝的会幕中（出 38:8）。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;行法术的用各种神奇的魔术迷惑人，一旦悔改后，就把书焚烧了以作惩治（徒 19:19）。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;给悔改之人的安慰&quot;&gt;给悔改之人的安慰&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;悔改之人立时蒙赦免。&lt;/strong&gt;“悔改的狀態就是得赦免的狀態”。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;神会把你的罪忘怀净尽。&lt;/strong&gt;神饶恕人的罪是到忘怀的地步，不会旧事重提，而是把罪投诸深海（弥 7:19）。就如同债主在账簿上抹除了债务，那件事即便再提出来，也不能损害他了。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;除掉悔改的拦阻&quot;&gt;除掉悔改的拦阻&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;作者列举了十项悔改的阻碍：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;体会不到自己需要悔改。&lt;/strong&gt;当感觉到事事如意、不需要悔改的时候就要当心了。真相是，人的老我永远会在，人每天都在犯罪，只是不自知。求神赐给我们一颗对罪敏感的心。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;以为悔改是很容易的事。&lt;/strong&gt;因为这样的想法，人会大胆犯罪，以为只要悔改就可以了。神确实会立即饶恕真悔改的信徒，然而悔改伴随着为罪忧伤、羞耻、恨罪等等难以承受的情绪，而且最后还要竭力修正自己的行为，做到真正离罪，这些都不是简单的事。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;对神的怜悯有恃无恐。&lt;/strong&gt;“但在你有赦免之恩，要叫人敬畏你。”（诗 130:4）神的赦免是叫人敬畏他，而并非纵容人犯罪。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;品行怠惰。&lt;/strong&gt;圣洁是需要竭力追求的，而不是把责任都推给神。虽然神已预定万事，但基督徒仍要履行自己的责任，这是不冲突的。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;罪中之乐。&lt;/strong&gt;罪必然有他吸引人的一面，不然不会那么多人前赴后继争相跳入一个又一个的陷阱。然而，罪中之乐难道不是转瞬即逝吗？难道不是在得到的那一刻便已失去吸引力了吗？为了暂时的欢愉而放弃永恒的喜乐，是否值得？&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;误以为悔改会剥夺我们的快乐。&lt;/strong&gt;“属世的欢乐，就如一声假笑，愁苦接踵而来。正如魔术师的棒，立时转为毒蛇；但属上帝的悔改，正如参孙的狮子藏着蜂蜜。”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;意气消沉。&lt;/strong&gt;一定要相信神的怜悯可以包容我们一切的过犯，耶稣基督的血可以遮盖一切的罪。“因为，他的怒气不过是转眼之间；他的恩典乃是一生之久。一宿虽然有哭泣，早晨便必欢呼。”（诗 30:5）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;希望侥幸得以赦免。&lt;/strong&gt;在神面前一切伪装都是无效的，不悔改的人存有侥幸心理认为神的怜悯是大的，却不知道神的公义也是大的。神的公义不允许他赦免不曾悔改的人，若他这样去行，那就违反了他本身。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;怕受讥诮和责备。&lt;/strong&gt;如果受到的责备是来自那无知不认识神的人，那又何须介意？因为悔改受责备好过不悔改被定罪。吐过受到的责备是来自于认识神的人，那又何须介意？耶稣基督被钉死在十架上所受的苦岂不是比受责备的苦更沉重？相比起来，责备算得了什么？&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;贪爱世界。&lt;/strong&gt;每个人都以属世的借口，来推辞基督邀请的筵席。“众人异口同声地推辞。头一个对他说：‘我买了一块地，必须去看看。请你准我辞了。’ 19 另一个说：‘我买了五对牛，要去试一试。请你准我辞了。’ 20 又有一个说：‘我才娶了妻子，所以不能去。’ ”这像不像我们因为繁重的学业、人情世故、买房投资等人间琐事而拖欠的祷告和认罪。我们不能只顾着殷勤耕作田产，而忘记了耕耘被荆棘堵塞的心田。作者说在 Sardinia 有一种乳香的香草，人吃多了会笑着死亡，世界正是这种香草。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;悔改良方&quot;&gt;悔改良方&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;如果读者还在罪当中受苦，请仔细思量下面的事：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;什么是罪？&lt;/strong&gt;罪所包含的邪恶就足以让人悔改不已。罪包含的邪恶有：偏离神、背弃神、罪伤害神、罪是极度的无知、罪最终引至绝望、罪中满污垢、罪是极丑陋的忘恩、罪使人卑贱、罪是亏损、罪是重担、罪是债项、罪迷惑欺哄人、罪是属灵的疾病、罪是个捆绑、罪有恶性循环的本能、罪带来苦恼麻烦、罪是荒谬的、罪是讨仇敌欢心、每一件罪都是在刺伤自己的灵魂、罪是属灵的死亡、犯罪引至定罪&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;什么是神的恩典？&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;消极的恩典。我们躲避过多少困难阻碍？逃掉过多少恐惧？不能只看我们得到的，也要看到神保护我们没有受到过的危险。&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;积极的恩典。包括：供养的恩典、拯救的恩典。&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;请留意神安排苦难的手法。&lt;/strong&gt;神通过苦难的方法对付人的自义，叫人谦卑来到他的面前。玛拿西的苦难带来悔改（历下 33:12），“他祈祷耶和华，耶和华就允准他的祈求，垂听他的祷告，使他归回耶路撒冷，仍坐国位。玛拿西这才知道惟独耶和华是　神。”大部分人在苦难的熬炼下，才能学会悔改归向神。悔改后便会发现，人生中遇到的荆棘不但不可怕，反而阻拦了我们通向死亡之路。此外，作者还提到神的审判是循序渐进的，一次次增加十字架的重量为了叫人转回。&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;数算一下我们有多少待算的账目。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;比较悔改与不悔改的景况。&lt;/strong&gt;悔改可以令一切归回安息，灵魂得到救赎和真自由；不悔改永远被罪捆绑，失去耶稣的怜悯和恩待，与神的圣洁永远无份。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 08:03:07 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/doctrine-of-repentance-3</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/doctrine-of-repentance-3</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>Doctrine of Repentance</category>
        
        <category>Christianity</category>
        
        <category>中文</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
